Seidenberg, Jacob Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records 5175
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records
1947-1972
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5175
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records of Jacob Seidenberg pertaining to the Taft-Hartley Maritime dispute.
5555882
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 19, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 01, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5031 A&B: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5194: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5935: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5988: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Labor laws and legislation -- United States; Collective bargaining -- United States; Seidenberg, Jacob; United States. Labor Management Relations Act, 1947
5555882
- Text of Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Cargo Agreement. New York Shipping Association and International Longshoremen's Association 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Union's Position for Resumption of Work August 26, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Order No. 11621 October 4, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Status of Negotiations as of October 4, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Order for Report and Supplementary Report Executive Order No. 11621 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notification of Presidential Board of Inquiries Executive Order No. 11621 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Presidential Board of Inquiry Labor disputes Affecting The Maritime Industry (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Supplemental Report to the President Certain Labor Disputes Affecting the Maritime Industry Nov 28, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Final Offer of Settlement for 2 Year Contract. Longshoremen and Clerks December 1, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- President's Board of Inquiry Attendees December 1, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sixth-Day Report to the President on the Labor Dispute Involving the Longshore Industry of the Pacific Congo December 5, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Dispatcher December 7, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Grievance Arbitration in Public Employer Disciplinary Cases Charles P. Fischboch December 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Negotiation Proposals West Gulf Coast International Longshoremen's Association Jan 19, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Memorandum of Agreement January 21, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Basic Agreement Notification and Correspondence January 23, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Presidential Board of Inquiry January 24, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Sixty-Day Report to Our President on the Labor Dispute Involving the Longshore Industry on the Atlantic and Gulf Coast January 25, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- NLRB Certification International Longshoremen's Association February 9, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Letter Regarding the Board of the Inquiry from J. Keith Mann February 24, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Awards No. 15-23 Public Law Board 516 (Folder 1 of 2) 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Awards No. 15-29 Public Law Board 516 (Folder 2 of 2) 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Public Law #525 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Public Law 525 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Public Law 525 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Public Law 525 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Public Law 525 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Public Board 525 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Public Law 525 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No.11 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 12-16 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 17 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 18 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 19 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 21 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 22 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 30 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 31 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 32-33 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 34 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 35-38 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 24-29 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 39-40 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 41 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 42 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 43 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 44-45 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Public Law Board 525 Award No. 46 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 14 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 10 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 12-13 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 24 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 11 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 9 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 8 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 7 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 5 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 4 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Public Law Board 516 Award No. 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)